<sect2 id="usage-profile">
  <title>Using profiles to extend your action</title>
  <para>
    There are some situations where you will want a given action behave
    slightly differently depending on the currently selected items or
    the current runtime environment.
  </para>
  <example>
    <title>Open a terminal here</title>
    <para>
      Say you have an action which opens a terminal in the current
      location.
    </para>
    <para>
      You have configured it to open your preferred terminal in the
      location your file manager currently points to.
    </para>
    <para>
      But what if you want to select a directory in your file manager,
      and directly open your terminal in this directory ? If you
      keep based on the current file manager location, your
      terminal will open in the parent of the targeted directory.
    </para>
    <para>
      One solution is to define a new profile to your action,
      configuring this profile to open the terminal in the
      targeted directory.
    </para>
    <para>
      At runtime, &prodname; will successively examine each profile
      attached to your action. If the first profile targets a file
      while you have selected a directory, then &prodname; will just
      try with your second profile.
    </para>
  </example>
  <para>To create a new profile, first select the action in the items list, then choose <menuchoice><!-- i18n: "File" is a menu item --><guisubmenu>File</guisubmenu><!-- i18n: "New profile" is a menu item --><guimenuitem>New profile</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.</para>
  <para>
    A new profile is created in your action.
  </para>
  <para>
    You can now define the conditions which must be met in order
    this profile be selected, and the command which will be executed.
  </para>
  
  <sect3 id="usage-profile-order">
    <title>Ordering the profiles inside an action</title>
    <para>
      At runtime, &prodname; will begin with examining the conditions
      set on your action.
    </para>
    <para>
      If these conditions (the action-conditions) are met, then &prodname;
      will examine in order each profile.
    </para>
    <para>
      If these conditions (the action-conditions) are met, then
      &prodname; will examine in order each profile.
    </para>
    <para>
      If no profile is found valid at runtime, then the action will be
      itself considered invalid, and will not be displayed in the file
      manager context menu.
    </para>
    <para>
      Profiles of an action are ordered, and they are examined in that
      order at runtime. The first profile whose conditions are met will
      be validated, and made selectable in the &caja; context menu.
    </para>
    <para>
      So, ordering of the profiles may be important for your action:
      the first valid profile found is the only one selected.
    </para>
    <para>
      You may order your profiles inside an action in two ways.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Cut the profile to be moved, select the profile before which
          you want your cut profile to be inserted, and paste it.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click on the profile to be moved, and drag it to its right place.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </sect3>
</sect2>
